# **Ekaterina Titova**

## Senior Software Engineer, Technical lead

Cell: (+1) 778 990 2704

Address: Vancouver, BC, Canada

Email: <a href="mailto:ektitova10@gmail.com">ektitova10@gmail.com</a>

**LinkedIn:** https://www.linkedin.com/in/ekaterina-titova-08431339/

## **Profile:**

Main expertise area is mobile and full stack development, technical management and coordination, architecture design and support with 10 years' work experience, which covers the following operation systems: Android, iOS, Windows, Symbian UIQ, Brew Mobile, Blackberry, and such programming languages as: Java SE (6 years), JavaScript, Kotlin, C (2 years), C++ (1,5 years), C#, Objective C, HTML, CSS.

**Stack of technologies:** RESTful services, PhoneGap, Cordova, STL, ASP.NET MVC, Blackberry, Brew Mobile OS, Symbian UIQ, Bootstrap 4.

## **Education:**

Master degree in Computer Science and Information Technology, Diploma with Honors

**2004 – 2010:** Nizhniy Novgorod Technical State University, Radio engineering and information technology department, Nizhniy Novgorod, Russia

**2009:** Android OS course (Symphony Teleca, Nizhniy Novgorod, Russia)

**2018:** Software Product Management Specialization on Coursera:

https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/specialization/certificate/F43EEL34U46L

**2018:** Basics of Web Development and Coding on Coursera.

## Languages:

English – Fluent, Russian – Native

## **Experience:**

Aug 2013 – May 2017 Samsung Electronics <u>www.samsung.com</u> Sr Software Engineer, Technical manager, Software Engineer

South Korea, Suwon

**Responsibilities:** remote technical management and coordination of a team of developers, requirements negotiation, planning, building architecture, research, code development, support, consulting and maintenance.

#### **Project Experience:**

• SmartView SDK library, Android, C#:

http://developer.samsung.com/tv/develop/extension-libraries/smart-view-sdk/download/

**SmartView SDK** provides API for mobile, tablet or PC to discover, connect and communicate with Samsung Smart TV s through the Android, iOS and JavaScript libraries.

**Achievements:** Research, architecture design, implementation and support (features: wake on wireless and connect to TV application, secure connection from mobile to TV, remote control TV from mobile)

• SmartView Application, Android:

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.samsung.smartviewad

**SmartView application** provides remote control functionality for Samsung TVs: changing channels, volume control, pointer movement, watching TV, sending and browse mobile content (video, photo, music) from mobile device to TV.

**Stack of technologies:** Java SE (Android), RESTful services, PhoneGap, Cordova, C#, ASP.NET MVC

Dec 2010 – July 2013 Mera NN www.merasws.com

Russia, Nizhny Novgorod

Positions: Sr Software Engineer, Software Engineer

**Responsibilities:** research, architecture design, code development, implementation and support **Project Experience:** 

- **Professional Application Suite, iOS** is an organizer for lawyers to track financial operations. Client-server architecture based.
- MERA.DVR Video Registrar application, Android

**Video Registrar application**: in-car video registrar (DVR) in your Android device; it continuously records what you see through your car's window during a trip. Application provides possibility to browse / play / manage video files, track your location, work with Google maps.

**Achievements:** research, initial architecture design and implementation. Work with project from the first stage till release to Google Play, support and maintenance

- **Verizon Navigator, Android, iOS, Blackberry** navigation application for Android, iOS and Blackberry mobile phones.
- Yandex.Taxi, Android application for ordering taxi with specific destination using maps. It has JavaScript back-end (cross platform) and Android and iOS UI wrappers (front-end).

Stack of technologies: Java SE (Android, Blackberry), Objective C, JavaScript

July 2007 – Nov 2010 **Symphony Teleca** www.symphonyteleca.com

Russia, Nizhny Novgorod

Positions: Software Engineer, Associate Software Engineer

Responsibilities: research, code development and support

## **Project Experience:**

- Application Multimedia project, Brew mobile platform, C: implementation and support of basic multimedia applications such as Media Gallery, Music Player and Camera for Brew mobile platform and CDMA cellphones
- Auto Unit Test Application Tool, Windrows, C# performs full automatic test procedure (tests selection, test setup, results collection) for mobile applications (Android and Brew platforms) C#, XML test scripts.
- **DLNA applications project, Symbian UIQ, C++:** Multimedia DLNA applications development: browsing available servers, permissions settings, exchanging content between devices

**Stack of technologies:** C, C++, C#, ASP.NET MVC, Java (Android), Brew OS, Brew Mobile OS, Symbian UIQ

## **Skills:**

- Deep thinker with an analytical approach
- Hard worker with a passionate attitude for excellence
- Fast learner: ability to quickly get up-to-speed on technologies, techniques, tools, or skills that I've never encountered before